in this video we're going to talk about
classes in GP and compare that to the
experience in business Central where we
will use templates to streamline the
creation of new customers vendors and
items to begin let's go to GP and look
at a customer class that I've already
created in this example we're grouping
our customers by region and I have some
preset information for customers in the
Northeast region for example we've
entered the finance charge credit limit
in salesperson assigned to this region
in addition if I select the accounts
button I want to make sure that the
sales account being posted to is for the
Northeast region
segment next if we go to one of the
customers assigned to that class we can
see that same information that we
entered on the template defaulted onto
the customer card for
us here we can see that the correct
salesperson is assigned to the customer
and and again selecting that accounts
button see lets us see that same
Northeast region sales
account now let's look at business
Central and how we can create templates
that allow us to easily set up
information we want for new customers
entered in the
system to navigate to the templates we
will select the search icon and enter
customer templates and then choose that
from the search
results I'll first give the new template
and name and then start filling in the
information that they'd like to default
for new or existing customers we have in
the
Northeast if you've noticed I don't see
the credit limit or salesperson fields
on the template form I can simply select
to personalize the form find the fields
that I want to add and drag them onto
the template
window now that I've added the credit
limit and salesperson fields to the
template I can select the proper value
for
each next we'll set the default business
and customer posting groups so that the
correct sales and accounts receivables
accounts are used for customers in this
group finally let's set that default
region Dimension value so that
transactions posted to the sales account
are categorized correctly similar to
using the Northeast segment value in GP
now that we have the customer template
configured let's create a new customer
and apply the
template when I select to create a new
customer you can see the various
templates I've created are displayed and
I can select that Northeast region
template in the customer window you can
see how the credit limit and salespeople
have defaulted in for me as well as the
right business and customer posting
groups we can also navigate to the
dimension for the customer and see that
the Northeast region has been defaulted
there as
well if I had existing customers that I
wanted to apply this template to I could
do that as
well lastly if you create a customer
with values you want to use another
customers you can create a template from
an existing customer
record and that's a quick look at how we
can use templates in business Central to
streamline data creation and improve
data
accuracy to learn more about business
Central see the following resources